Finding Aid for the Paul B. MacCready Papers, 1931-2002 MacCreadyPB
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
- Biographical and Correspondence, 5
  - Articles and other publications about MacCready, his projects and his team, 5
    - August 23, 1977: beginning of man-flight, Hang Glider, Vol. 4, no. 28, 1977 August 8; MacCreadyPB_05_05_020_09 (Box 5.20, Folder 9)
    - Gossamer Condor attains man-powered flight goal, American Aviation Historical Society Journal, Vol. 22, no. 3, 1977 Fall; MacCreadyPB_05_05_020_10 (Box 5.20, Folder 10)
    - American claims Kremer man-power prize, Flight International, 1977 September 3; MacCreadyPB_05_05_020_11 (Box 5.20, Folder 11)
    - After 18 years, bicycle-powered pterodactyl wins Kremer crown, NBAA Convention News, 1977 September 29; MacCreadyPB_05_05_020_12 (Box 5.20, Folder 12)
    - The Condor flies!, Aircraft, Vol. 57, no. 1, 1977 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_01 (Box 5.21, Folder 1)
    - Gossamer Condor, Glider Rider, 1977 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_02 (Box 5.21, Folder 2)
    - Gossamer wings, Scientific American, 1977 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_03 (Box 5.21, Folder 3)
    - Another small step, Soaring, 1977 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_04 (Box 5.21, Folder 4)
    - Man-powered flight!, AIAA Newsletter, 1977 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_05 (Box 5.21, Folder 5)
    - First really promising U.S. man-powered aircraft, Popular Science, 1977 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_06 (Box 5.21, Folder 6)
    - Gossamer Condor reaches a dream, Industrial Research, 1977 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_07 (Box 5.21, Folder 7)
    - Human-powered aircraft brings family together, Pasadena Starnews, 1977 October 3; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_08 (Box 5.21, Folder 8)
    - How Gossamer Condor was pedalled through the sky to win £50000, New Scientist, 1977 October 6; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_09 (Box 5.21, Folder 9)
    - America's man-powered prizewinner, Flight International, 1977 October 29; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_10 (Box 5.21, Folder 10)
    - Aviation milestone, National Pilots Association News, Vol. 17, no. 11, 1977 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_11 (Box 5.21, Folder 11)
    - Ein Flug mit menschlicher Kraft, der 200000 Mark einbrachte!, Radmarkt, 1977 November 18; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_12 (Box 5.21, Folder 12)
    - Pedaling into history, Science Digest, 1977 December; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_13 (Box 5.21, Folder 13)
    - Gossamer Condor, Model Aviation, 1977 December; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_14 (Box 5.21, Folder 14)
    - If Da Vinci could see us now!, FAA World, 1977 December; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_15 (Box 5.21, Folder 15)
    - I pedaled the mile to aviation's big prize, Popular Mechanics, 1977 December; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_16 (Box 5.21, Folder 16)
    - The Gossamer Condor, Human Power vol. 1, no. 1, 1977-1978; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_17 (Box 5.21, Folder 17)
    - Magazine covers, 1977-1978; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_18 (Box 5.21, Folder 18)
    - Comrades of Condor, Aviation Journal, No. 59, 1978; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_19 (Box 5.21, Folder 19)
    - Gossamer Condor, Aerospace Magazine, 1978; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_20 (Box 5.21, Folder 20)
    - Gossamer Albatross: new man-powered Super Bird; an article by Jim Joseph, 1978; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_21 (Box 5.21, Folder 21)
    - The Winner, Popular Science, 1978 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_22 (Box 5.21, Folder 22)
    - The flight of the Gossamer Condor, National Geographic, Vol. 153, no. 1, 1978 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_23 (Box 5.21, Folder 23)
    - Human-powered flight, National Geographic World, No. 28, 1978 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_24 (Box 5.21, Folder 24)
    - Brain-powered flight, Technology Review, 1978 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_25 (Box 5.21, Folder 25)
    - World's first WPA (Woman powered airplane), Homebuilt and Craft, 1978 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_26 (Box 5.21, Folder 26)
    - Gossamer Condor, Air pictorial, 1978 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_27 (Box 5.21, Folder 27)
    - Menneskedreven flyvning mulig, Flyv, 1978 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_28 (Box 5.21, Folder 28)
    - Gossamer Condor, Sport Aviation, 1978 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_021_29 (Box 5.21, Folder 29)
    - Man powered airplane, Israel Aviation and Space Magazine, Vol. 26, 1978 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_01 (Box 5.22, Folder 1)
    - Bryan Allen, Glider Rider, 1978 March; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_02 (Box 5.22, Folder 2)
    - Jack Lambie tells his story of the Gossamer Condor, Aero Modeller, 1978 March; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_03 (Box 5.22, Folder 3)
    - Alumni feature: Paul MacCready '43H, Hopkins, 1978 Spring; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_04 (Box 5.22, Folder 4)
    - The improbable, prize-winning Gossamer Condor, Air & Space, Vol. 1, no. 2, 1978 April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_05 (Box 5.22, Folder 5)
    - A new challenge in human-powered flight, Soaring, 1978 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_06 (Box 5.22, Folder 6)
    - Caltech honors four graduates on Seminar Day, Caltech News, Vol. 12, no. 4, 1978 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_07 (Box 5.22, Folder 7)
    - Man powered flight, Omni, 1978 December; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_08 (Box 5.22, Folder 8)
    - Pedaling for $100,000, Popular Science, 1978 December; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_09 (Box 5.22, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous articles about the Gossamer Condor, folder 2, 1978-1980; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_10 (Box 5.22, Folder 10)
    - Gossamer Odyssey by Morton Grosser notes and manuscript, 1978 - 1981; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_11 (Box 5.22, Folder 11)
    - Gossamer Odyssey by Morton Grosser, people's CVs and biographical details, 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_12 (Box 5.22, Folder 12)
    - Flight of the Albatross, Aviation Quarterly Vol. 5, no. 1, 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_13 (Box 5.22, Folder 13)
    - Cross-Channel Albatross, Evening News, 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_14 (Box 5.22, Folder 14)
    - Newspapers cartoons, 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_15 (Box 5.22, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper articles about the Gossamer Albatross Channel crossing, 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_16 (Box 5.22, Folder 16)
    - La bicyclette du ciel, Sciences & Avenir, Special no. 23, ca. 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_17 (Box 5.22, Folder 17)
    - Du Pont sponsoring human-powered flight across English Channel, ca. 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_18 (Box 5.22, Folder 18)
    - Genius of the Gossamer Albatross, Aviation Travel Times, Vol. 1, no. 1, ca. 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_19 (Box 5.22, Folder 19)
    - Letalsko zmagoslavje Gossamer Albatrossa, Krila, ca. 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_20 (Box 5.22, Folder 20)
    - Le Gossamer Albatross ou...je pédale, donc je vole!, Spirou, ca. 1979; MacCreadyPB_05_05_022_21 (Box 5.22, Folder 21)
    - 250.000 francs pour voler comme Icare, Radio TV Je Vois Tout, 1979 January 25; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_01 (Box 5.23, Folder 1)
    - English Channel flight being tested on Terminal Island, News Pilot, No. 276, 1979 January 30; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_02 (Box 5.23, Folder 2)
    - Gossamer wing will try to lift $200,000 prize, Los Angeles Times, 1979 February 1; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_03 (Box 5.23, Folder 3)
    - MacCready set for Channel flight, Flight International, 1979 February 10; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_04 (Box 5.23, Folder 4)
    - Channel manpower hopefuls weigh up the problems, Flight International, 1979 February 17; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_05 (Box 5.23, Folder 5)
    - L'avion à pédales sur la Manche, Sciences & Avenir, 1979 March; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_06 (Box 5.23, Folder 6)
    - MacCready HPA groomed for Channel flight, Soaring and Motorgliding, Vol. 43, no. 3, 1979 March; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_07 (Box 5.23, Folder 7)
    - On Gossamer wings, The Guardian, 1979 March 22; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_08 (Box 5.23, Folder 8)
    - The Channel challenge: manpowered flight's second giant step, Popular Mechanics, 1979 April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_09 (Box 5.23, Folder 9)
    - The Gossamer Condor, Highlights: The Monthly Book For Children, 1979 April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_10 (Box 5.23, Folder 10)
      Article by Tyler MacCready
    - The Gossamer Albatross, Plastics, Vol. 5, no. 6, 1979 May; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_11 (Box 5.23, Folder 11)
    - Maiden flight of the Gossamer Albatross, Hang Gliding, 1979 May; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_12 (Box 5.23, Folder 12)
    - Lehre vom Habicht, Der Spiegel, no. 19, 1979 May 7; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_13 (Box 5.23, Folder 13)
    - Bicycle to cross Channel?, Pasadena Star-News, 1979 May 17; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_14 (Box 5.23, Folder 14)
    - A trip to Calais on Gossamer wings, Daily Express, 1979 May 17; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_15 (Box 5.23, Folder 15)
    - Ikarus im Remi-Sattel, Tour, 1979 May-June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_16 (Box 5.23, Folder 16)
    - The Gossamer Condor, Astronautics & Aeronautics, 1979 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_17 (Box 5.23, Folder 17)
    - Premiere traversée de la Manche par un'avion à pédales, 1979 June 12; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_18 (Box 5.23, Folder 18)
    - Man-powered flight: science gives wings to an old idea, The New York Times, 1979 June 13; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_19 (Box 5.23, Folder 19)
    - Flying bicycle crosses Channel, Morning Star, 1979 June 13; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_20 (Box 5.23, Folder 20)
    - California man pedals plane across Channel, Los Angeles Times, 1979 June 13; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_21 (Box 5.23, Folder 21)
    - No longer a flight of fancy, Kent Evening Post, 1979 June 14; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_22 (Box 5.23, Folder 22)
    - Icarus on a bicycle, Glasgow Herald, 1979 June 15; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_23 (Box 5.23, Folder 23)
    - Designer of Albatross praises pedalling pilot, Daily Telegraph, 1979 June 15; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_24 (Box 5.23, Folder 24)
    - Up and over the Channel he goes, East Kent Times Mail, 1979 June 15; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_25 (Box 5.23, Folder 25)
    - Countdown to aviation history, Folkestone Herald, 1979 June 16; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_26 (Box 5.23, Folder 26)
    - The flight of the Gossamer Albatross, The Detroit News, 1979 June 17; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_27 (Box 5.23, Folder 27)
    - Man-power flight: vision of future, Chicago Tribune, 1979 June 17; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_28 (Box 5.23, Folder 28)
    - System propels design of 'Gossamer Albatross', Computerworld, 1979 June 18; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_29 (Box 5.23, Folder 29)
    - Le Gossamer Albatross a traversé la Manche, Air et Cosmos, 1979 June 23; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_30 (Box 5.23, Folder 30)
    - Gossamer Albatross conquers English Channel, Flight International, 1979 June 23; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_31 (Box 5.23, Folder 31)
    - Odyssey of the Albatross, Time, 1979 June 25; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_32 (Box 5.23, Folder 32)
    - The Albatross flies, Newsweek, 1979 June 25; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_33 (Box 5.23, Folder 33)
    - Wondrous wings across the water, Sports Illustrated, 1979 June 25; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_34 (Box 5.23, Folder 34)
    - After the Channel, what's next?, DuPont News, 1979 July; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_35 (Box 5.23, Folder 35)
    - Gossamer Albatross success, Southland Flyer, 1979 July; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_36 (Box 5.23, Folder 36)
    - Picnic has it all - hero and flag, Los Angeles Times, 1979 July 5; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_37 (Box 5.23, Folder 37)
    - Flying high on Gossamer wings, Los Angeles Times, 1979 July 6; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_38 (Box 5.23, Folder 38)
    - Will it cross English Channel, Los Angeles Times, 1979 July 8; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_39 (Box 5.23, Folder 39)
    - Gossamer Albatross: anatomy of a cross-channel flier, Flight International, 1979 July 28; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_40 (Box 5.23, Folder 40)
    - Flying Albatross is sailing home, Journal of Commerce, 1979 July 31; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_41 (Box 5.23, Folder 41)
    - The Gossamer Albatross, Soaring and Motorgliding, Vol. 43, no. 8, 1979 August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_42 (Box 5.23, Folder 42)
    - Bryan Allen interview, Glider Rider, Issue 43, 1979 August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_023_43 (Box 5.23, Folder 43)
    - Cross-Channel Albatross, Aeroplane Monthly, 1979 August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_01 (Box 5.24, Folder 1)
    - Gossamer Albatross - Channel conqueror, Aerospace, 1979 August-September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_02 (Box 5.24, Folder 2)
    - "Gossamer Albatross" conquers the English Channel, Measure, 1979 August-September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_03 (Box 5.24, Folder 3)
    - The Gossamer Albatross, Aero Modeller, 1979 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_04 (Box 5.24, Folder 4)
    - Die Aufgabe, Aerokurier, 1979 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_05 (Box 5.24, Folder 5)
    - Gossamer Albatross: afterthoughts, Experimental Aircraft Association, 1979 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_06 (Box 5.24, Folder 6)
    - Paul MacCready interview, Delta Info, 1979 September 22; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_07 (Box 5.24, Folder 7)
    - MacCready's Albatross, FAA General Aviation News, 1979 September-October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_08 (Box 5.24, Folder 8)
    - Flight of the Gossamer Albatross, Du Pont Magazine, 1979 September-October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_09 (Box 5.24, Folder 9)
    - Winged victory of "Gossamer Albatross", National Geographic, Vol. 156, no. 5, 1979 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_10 (Box 5.24, Folder 10)
    - Pasadena Star-News short articles, 1979-1989; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_11 (Box 5.24, Folder 11)
    - Paul MacCready o Gossamer Albatrassu, Letecky & Kosmonautica, ca. 1980; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_12 (Box 5.24, Folder 12)
    - On Gossamer wings, Reader's Digest, 1980 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_13 (Box 5.24, Folder 13)
    - Flying by the power of human muscles, Spectrum, 1980 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_14 (Box 5.24, Folder 14)
    - From Icarus to the something bowl, The New York Times, 1980 January 21; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_15 (Box 5.24, Folder 15)
    - The Barnaby Lecture - the story behind the Albatross, Thermal, 1980 January-February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_16 (Box 5.24, Folder 16)
    - Aerospace talks to Dr Paul MacCready, Aerospace, 1980 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_17 (Box 5.24, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous mentions of Gossamer Albatross, NASA X-Press, 1980 February 8 - 1980 April 4; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_18 (Box 5.24, Folder 18)
    - Human powered flight, AIAA student journal, 1980 Spring; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_19 (Box 5.24, Folder 19)
    - Icarus on a bicycle, Power Transmission Design, 1980 April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_20 (Box 5.24, Folder 20)
    - The Exploratorium Gossamer Albatross Edition, Vol. 4, Issue 1, 1980 April-May; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_21 (Box 5.24, Folder 21)
    - Human-powered flight pioneer addresses SRL, Savannah River Plant News, 1980 May 29; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_22 (Box 5.24, Folder 22)
    - Solar power takes wing, DuPont News, Vol. 9, no. 6, 1980 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_23 (Box 5.24, Folder 23)
    - A visit with Bryan Allen, American Wheelmen, Vol. 16, No. 6, 1980 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_24 (Box 5.24, Folder 24)
    - Designers cheer creator of man-powered aircraft, Denver Post, 1980 June 20; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_25 (Box 5.24, Folder 25)
    - Inventor of 1st man-powered airplane has designs on energy conservation, 1980 June 20; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_26 (Box 5.24, Folder 26)
    - The Gossamer dream, Guideposts, 1980 July; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_27 (Box 5.24, Folder 27)
    - The screw propeller, Scientific American, Vol. 243, 1980 July; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_28 (Box 5.24, Folder 28)
    - Program manager - endangered species?, National Defense, 1980 August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_29 (Box 5.24, Folder 29)
    - Off into the wild blue - on sun power, U.S. News & World Report, 1980 August 18; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_30 (Box 5.24, Folder 30)
    - On butterfly wings, this time, WPI Journal, 1980 Fall; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_31 (Box 5.24, Folder 31)
    - Solar challenger, Aero modeller, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_32 (Box 5.24, Folder 32)
    - A Gossamer Penguin, Popular Science, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_33 (Box 5.24, Folder 33)
    - L' avion solaire a volé de ses propres cellules, Science & Vie, no. 756, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_34 (Box 5.24, Folder 34)
    - Gossamer Penguin makes historical solar flight, RC Modeler, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_024_35 (Box 5.24, Folder 35)
    - Gossamer Penguin flies, Sport Aviation, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_01 (Box 5.25, Folder 1)
    - New solar-powered plane, Homebuilt Aircraft, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_02 (Box 5.25, Folder 2)
    - Gossamer birds, flights of the imagination, Hospital Practice, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_03 (Box 5.25, Folder 3)
    - Teacher/Pilot soars into history, CTA/NEA Action, 1980 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_04 (Box 5.25, Folder 4)
    - Flygfärdig Pröva dina vingar hos DuPont, Svenska Dogbladel, 1980 September 3; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_05 (Box 5.25, Folder 5)
    - Tech front lines: aviation, Popular Mechanics, 1980 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_06 (Box 5.25, Folder 6)
    - Flight of the Penguin, Discover, 1980 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_07 (Box 5.25, Folder 7)
    - Penguin lifts solar awareness, Industrial Research and Development, 1980 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_08 (Box 5.25, Folder 8)
    - MacCready Solar Challenger, Flug Revue, 1980 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_09 (Box 5.25, Folder 9)
    - Die Sonne bringt es in die Luft, Bunte, no. 44, 1980 October 23; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_10 (Box 5.25, Folder 10)
    - Pedal power to the sky, Insight Magazine, 1980 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_11 (Box 5.25, Folder 11)
    - Gossamer Albatross to "Fly" at SMM, The Science Museum of Minnesota Encounters, Vol. 3, no. 10, 1980 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_12 (Box 5.25, Folder 12)
    - A prize idea: reward the invention, not the feasibility study, Inc., 1980 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_13 (Box 5.25, Folder 13)
    - Solar Challenger miscellaneous articles, 1980-1988; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_14 (Box 5.25, Folder 14)
    - Der Mensch fliegt zum ersten Mal aus eigener Kraft, Deutsche Lufthansa..., 1981; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_15 (Box 5.25, Folder 15)
    - Dr. Paul MacCready, California Business, 1981 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_16 (Box 5.25, Folder 16)
    - A modern Icarus reaches to the sun for power to fly, Smithsonian, 1981 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_17 (Box 5.25, Folder 17)
    - Sun Chariot, The Stater, Vol. 53, no. 6, 1981 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_18 (Box 5.25, Folder 18)
    - On a clear day you can fly forever, Sports Illustrated, 1981 February 16; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_19 (Box 5.25, Folder 19)
    - Le Solar Challenger symbole des économies d'énergie, L'Aeronautique et L'Astronautique, 88, 1981 March; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_20 (Box 5.25, Folder 20)
    - Janice Brown expects to conquer the wild blue yonder in the world's first solar-powered airplane, US, 1981 March 3; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_21 (Box 5.25, Folder 21)
    - Something to think about, Time, Vol. 117, no. 14, 1981 April 6; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_22 (Box 5.25, Folder 22)
    - How the Gossamer Albatross conquered the Channel, Technology Review, 1981 May-June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_23 (Box 5.25, Folder 23)
    - Nouveaux détails sur le Solar Challenger, Air et Cosmos 861, 1981 May 23; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_24 (Box 5.25, Folder 24)
    - On a wing and a dare, American Way, 1981 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_025_25 (Box 5.25, Folder 25)
    - Les défis de l'avion solaire, Sciences and Avenir, 1981 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_01 (Box 5.26, Folder 1)
    - Vol solaire et avions ultre-légers, Bulletin Technique du Bureau Veritas, Vol. 63, no. 6, 1981 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_02 (Box 5.26, Folder 2)
    - Solar Challenger, Aeromodeller, 1981 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_03 (Box 5.26, Folder 3)
    - Le avion solaire offre de incroyable possibilites, Air et Cosmos, 863, 1981 June 6; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_04 (Box 5.26, Folder 4)
    - A Wright-minded pioneer, Paul MacCready, develops a plane powered by the sun, People, 1981 June 8; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_05 (Box 5.26, Folder 5)
    - Flying by the sun, Telegraph Sunday Magazine, 1981 June 14; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_06 (Box 5.26, Folder 6)
    - Planes that fly by the Sun, New Scientist, 1981 June 25; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_07 (Box 5.26, Folder 7)
    - Sun-powered airplane crosses Channel, New York Times, 1981 July; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_08 (Box 5.26, Folder 8)
    - Scommessa con il sole, Scienza e Vita, 1981 July; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_09 (Box 5.26, Folder 9)
    - On peut voler et voyager avec moins de 3000, Air et Cosmos, 1981 July 18; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_10 (Box 5.26, Folder 10)
    - Icarus would have loved it, Time, 1981 July 20; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_11 (Box 5.26, Folder 11)
    - Soaring on a sunbeam, Newsweek, 1981 July 20; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_12 (Box 5.26, Folder 12)
    - Le Dr. Paul MacCready aux XVe journées in Bulletin Technique du Bureau Veritas, Vol. 63, no. 7-8, 1981 July-August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_13 (Box 5.26, Folder 13)
    - Le succès de l'avion solaire, Sciences & Avenir, 1981 August; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_14 (Box 5.26, Folder 14)
    - Paul MacCready: on Gossamer wings, Discover, 1981 September; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_15 (Box 5.26, Folder 15)
    - Dr. Paul MacCready toward a rational use of power, Mother Earth News, 1981 September-October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_16 (Box 5.26, Folder 16)
    - Solar Challenger, Model Aviation, 1981 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_17 (Box 5.26, Folder 17)
    - The 'Solar Challenger' and solar flight, Bulletin Technique du Bureau, Vol. 10, no. 4, 1981 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_18 (Box 5.26, Folder 18)
    - En marge de la traversée de la Manche par le Solar Challenger, Bulletin Technique du Bureau Veritas, Vol. 63, no. 10, 1981 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_19 (Box 5.26, Folder 19)
    - On Friday October 23 solar electric flight, AIAA Newsletter, 1981 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_20 (Box 5.26, Folder 20)
    - A tale of two birds, Desert, 1981 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_21 (Box 5.26, Folder 21)
    - MacCready's Solar Challenger conquers sky, Sun, 1982 February; MacCreadyPB_05_05_026_22 (Box 5.26, Folder 22)
    - Icarus redeemed, The Stanford magazine, 1982 Spring; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_01 (Box 5.27, Folder 1)
    - "Unorthodox approach needed" to solve today's problems, U.S. News, 1982 August 2; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_02 (Box 5.27, Folder 2)
    - Bionic Bat, Omni, ca. 1983; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_03 (Box 5.27, Folder 3)
    - Pedal power: pilot report on the ultimate ultralights, Ultralight Pilot, Vol.2, no. 2, 1983 March/April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_04 (Box 5.27, Folder 4)
    - An interview with Dr. Paul B. MacCready by Bob Cheney, 1983 May 31; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_05 (Box 5.27, Folder 5)
    - Putting the wings on man, Yale: alumni magazine and journal, 1983 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_06 (Box 5.27, Folder 6)
    - An interview with Paul MacCready, Free Inquiry, 1983 Fall; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_07 (Box 5.27, Folder 7)
    - The wings of Mercury, Ultralight Aircraft, 1984 April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_08 (Box 5.27, Folder 8)
    - Bionic bat, Air Progress Ultralights, Vol. 2, no. 3, 1984 April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_09 (Box 5.27, Folder 9)
    - Human-powered flight, MD, 1984 April; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_10 (Box 5.27, Folder 10)
    - Bionic Valley, Volibre, 95, 1984 June; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_11 (Box 5.27, Folder 11)
    - Eight miles high, sniffing carbon dioxide, New Scientist, 1984 September 27; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_12 (Box 5.27, Folder 12)
    - A fossil that flies, Discover, 1984 November; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_13 (Box 5.27, Folder 13)
    - Is it a bird? A plane?, Lens, 1985 January; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_14 (Box 5.27, Folder 14)
    - The amateur scientist: a field formula for calculating the speed and flight efficiency of a soaring bird, Scientific American, 1985 March; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_15 (Box 5.27, Folder 15)
    - One-manpower flight, Ahlan Wasahlan, Vol. 9, no. 10, 1985 October; MacCreadyPB_05_05_027_16 (Box 5.27, Folder 16)